<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ringing Room on Running a Tower</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/</link><description>Recent content in Ringing Room on Running a Tower</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><atom:link href="https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ringing Boxes</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/boxes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/boxes/</guid><description>Ringing Boxes # Their design and construction.
The following, written by David Roskelly, was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
General Remarks on Box Design # Ringing boxes are one of the ubiquitous but often despised necessities of ringing. They are often heavy, they take up space in a ringing room which, in most cases, has little enough space to begin with and many ringers don&amp;rsquo;t like using them anyway.</description></item><item><title>Lighting</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/lighting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/lighting/</guid><description>Lighting # In and around towers.
The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Figure 1: Is this the state of the art in your tower? This old gas lamp would be better conserved properly for its engineering heritage value
Introduction # Lighting in and around a tower is often taken for granted until it is not working!
As a consequence of significant technical developments in lighting in the last few years, most people now benefit from good quality artificial light in their domestic, leisure and professional environments.</description></item><item><title>Handbells</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/handbells/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/handbells/</guid><description>Handbells # A brief guide
The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Figure 1: Part of a set of hand bells
Introduction # In the months whilst ringing was restricted due to the COVID pandemic, the interest in ringing handbells increased, including outside during warmer weather. This note aims to summarise some points that people may wish to consider.
Musical handbells are usually in tuned sets, unlike small school bells, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>