<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Running a Tower</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/</link><description>Recent content on Running a Tower</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><atom:link href="https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bells not rung regularly</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/irregular/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/irregular/</guid><description>Bells not rung regularly # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Figure 1: Infrequently used ringing room
We no longer have a team of bell ringers in our village. What do we do to ensure that the bells remain in good order?&amp;quot; # The answer to this question is complex, as it depends on many factors: the number of times they may be rung and for how long; frequency and quality of past maintenance and inspections; age/type of the installation (old-style or modern); whether belfry and tower is generally well maintained; enthusiasm of the tower authority; and so on.</description></item><item><title>Bells in Your Care</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/communication/yourcare/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/communication/yourcare/</guid><description>Bells in Your Care # Some notes for incumbents and churchwardens who find themselves responsible for a ring of church bells.
The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Bell Ringing # The sound of church bells ringing out can provide very loud evidence of the existence of an active church with an active congregation and you are fortunate to have bells in your care.</description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/communication/faqs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/communication/faqs/</guid><description>Frequently Asked Questions # These are some questions that are often asked by bell ringers. The answers are based on Church of England practice, so may vary elsewhere across the world and denominations. The following was written by The Guild of Clerical Ringers, in 2020, and was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Getting to know the people involved in the church where we ring # What is the difference between a vicar, a curate, an incumbent, a priest?</description></item><item><title>Insurance</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/formalities/insurance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/formalities/insurance/</guid><description>Insurance and Ringing # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
This Guidance Note offers advice to individual ringers, ringing organisations, Parochial Church Councils and clergy regarding factors to consider regarding insurance while ringing tower bells and in other issues related to ringing.
Most tower bells come under the jurisdiction of the Church of England, so this Guidance Note has been produced with this in mind.</description></item><item><title>Data Protection Guidance</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/formalities/gdpr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/formalities/gdpr/</guid><description>Data Protection Guidance # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website and was written in 2018.
Overview # The GDPR was applicable in EU member states from 25 May 2018. It did not require national legislation to be implemented and when the UK left the EU, the GDPR - like other directly applicable EU legislation - became part of the UK’s domestic law under the European Union (Withdrawal) Bill.</description></item><item><title>Health &amp; Safety Policy</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/healthsafetypolicy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/healthsafetypolicy/</guid><description>Health &amp;amp; Safety # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Advice for Bell Ringers # This document aims to help bell ringing societies/guilds/associations prepare a Health and Safety Policy for all activities of the society. (In these notes, the word society’ will be used regardless of the title of the society, guild or association concerned.)
Under common law, voluntary organisations and individual volunteers have a ‘duty of care’ to each other and to those who may be affected by their activities.</description></item><item><title>Risk Assessment</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/riskassessment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/riskassessment/</guid><description>Risk Assessment Guidance # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # Most towers with rings of bells are within the jurisdiction of the Church of England. While that is the focus of this document, the principles apply to rings of bells in towers owned by other organisations, in churches of other denominations, and churches elsewhere in the world. Local legislation and circumstances should always be considered.</description></item><item><title>Risk Assessment extended</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/riskassessmentextended/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/riskassessmentextended/</guid><description>Risk Assessment Guidance where the bells have not been rung for an extended period. # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # These notes offer advice about issues to consider in a health and safety risk assessment of the bells and tower prior to the bells being rung after an extended period (several months or more) during which they have not been rung.</description></item><item><title>Fire Protection</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/fireprevention/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/fireprevention/</guid><description>Fire Protection and Risk Assessment # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # These notes offer advice about specific issues that may affect bell ringers and the bell tower when considering fire safety and fire protection. The notes may assist the tower authority and bell ringers; they do not intend to provide comprehensive information about fire protection and fire risk assessments more generally.</description></item><item><title>Security</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/security/</guid><description>Security of Towers and Bell Ringers # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # These notes are written to help bell ringers consider their own security and that of the towers that they occupy when ringing. The principles underlying these notes apply to many buildings regardless of function or ownership, and activities. Here we highlight factors that relate specifically to ringers and ringing, rather than those that are more generic.</description></item><item><title>Tower Access</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/toweraccess/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/toweraccess/</guid><description>Tower Access # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # No matter how comfortable and well equipped your ringing room or how excellent the go of the bells, if you can&amp;rsquo;t reach them safely they&amp;rsquo;re not much use to you. For that reason it is well worth considering the state of the access route to the tower.
All towers are different and each will present a corresponding set of unique circumstances which will affect the decisions made with regard to the access route.</description></item><item><title>Ringing Boxes</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/boxes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/boxes/</guid><description>Ringing Boxes # Their design and construction.
The following, written by David Roskelly, was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
General Remarks on Box Design # Ringing boxes are one of the ubiquitous but often despised necessities of ringing. They are often heavy, they take up space in a ringing room which, in most cases, has little enough space to begin with and many ringers don&amp;rsquo;t like using them anyway.</description></item><item><title>Lighting</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/lighting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/ringingroom/lighting/</guid><description>Lighting # In and around towers.
The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Figure 1: Is this the state of the art in your tower? This old gas lamp would be better conserved properly for its engineering heritage value
Introduction # Lighting in and around a tower is often taken for granted until it is not working!
As a consequence of significant technical developments in lighting in the last few years, most people now benefit from good quality artificial light in their domestic, leisure and professional environments.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Agenda</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/agenda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/agenda/</guid><description>Draft Agenda # The following is an annotated draft of an agenda. A version of this, without the annotation, can be downloaded here.
Agenda for Annual Meeting of XXXX ringers at XXXX on DATE at TIME # Prayers and opening remarks. # Prayers are probably only relevant if the tower is part of a religious institution. If it is and a member of the clergy is present, they will perform this and may chair the meeting.</description></item><item><title>Appointment of Tower Captain</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/towercaptain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/towercaptain/</guid><description>Appointment of Bell Ringing Tower Captain - A Guide for Bell-Ringers and Churches # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # This note offers advice to ringers and churches about the appointment of the ‘Tower Captain’ in a church with bells. The person appointed may not be called the ‘Tower Captain’ in all towers – ‘Ringing Master’ is another title that is often used, or that may be used for another person with different responsibilities.</description></item><item><title>Planning ringing</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/planning/</guid><description>Planning ringing # These are only suggestions of ways of arranging ringing. Timing # REMEMBER
Not all ringers will arrive on time. Allow for greeting, hanging up coats, etc. Bells may have to be raised and lowered which may take up to 15 minutes and reduce the time to achieve aims. Aim to give everyone at least one piece of useful and satisfying ringing. Approximate timings of touches (used here to mean any piece of ringing): 120 changes of Doubles or Minor takes 4-5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Organising an Outing</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/outing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/outing/</guid><description>Organising an Outing # Figure 1: Appledore, Kent
A ringing outing can be an enjoyable and useful way of introducing ringers to a wider variety of bells than they might otherwise encounter.
It can help those involved to improve bell control and ringing skills, as it is like having multiple practices in one day.
Most importantly, it is a very good way of getting the ringers together socially.
Almost all towers are available, as long as the right people are contacted.</description></item></channel></rss>