<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Ringers on Running a Tower</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/</link><description>Recent content in The Ringers on Running a Tower</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><atom:link href="https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Meeting Agenda</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/agenda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/agenda/</guid><description>Draft Agenda # The following is an annotated draft of an agenda. A version of this, without the annotation, can be downloaded here.
Agenda for Annual Meeting of XXXX ringers at XXXX on DATE at TIME # Prayers and opening remarks. # Prayers are probably only relevant if the tower is part of a religious institution. If it is and a member of the clergy is present, they will perform this and may chair the meeting.</description></item><item><title>Appointment of Tower Captain</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/towercaptain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/towercaptain/</guid><description>Appointment of Bell Ringing Tower Captain - A Guide for Bell-Ringers and Churches # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # This note offers advice to ringers and churches about the appointment of the ‘Tower Captain’ in a church with bells. The person appointed may not be called the ‘Tower Captain’ in all towers – ‘Ringing Master’ is another title that is often used, or that may be used for another person with different responsibilities.</description></item><item><title>Planning ringing</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/planning/</guid><description>Planning ringing # These are only suggestions of ways of arranging ringing. Timing # REMEMBER
Not all ringers will arrive on time. Allow for greeting, hanging up coats, etc. Bells may have to be raised and lowered which may take up to 15 minutes and reduce the time to achieve aims. Aim to give everyone at least one piece of useful and satisfying ringing. Approximate timings of touches (used here to mean any piece of ringing): 120 changes of Doubles or Minor takes 4-5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Organising an Outing</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/outing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/buildingateam/outing/</guid><description>Organising an Outing # Figure 1: Appledore, Kent
A ringing outing can be an enjoyable and useful way of introducing ringers to a wider variety of bells than they might otherwise encounter.
It can help those involved to improve bell control and ringing skills, as it is like having multiple practices in one day.
Most importantly, it is a very good way of getting the ringers together socially.
Almost all towers are available, as long as the right people are contacted.</description></item></channel></rss>