<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Formalities on Running a Tower</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/formalities/</link><description>Recent content in Formalities on Running a Tower</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-uk</language><atom:link href="https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/formalities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Insurance</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/formalities/insurance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/formalities/insurance/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="insurance-and-ringing"&gt;
 Insurance and Ringing
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#insurance-and-ringing"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the &lt;a href="docs/glossary/#cccbr"&gt;CCCBR&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Guidance Note offers advice to individual ringers, ringing organisations, &lt;a href="docs/glossary/#pcc"&gt;Parochial Church Councils&lt;/a&gt; and clergy regarding factors to consider regarding insurance while ringing tower bells and in other issues related to ringing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most tower bells come under the jurisdiction of the &lt;a href="docs/glossary/#church-of-england"&gt;Church of England&lt;/a&gt;, so this Guidance Note has been produced with this in mind. However, most of the principles addressed will apply to Churches of other denominations and bells outside church ownership and / or control, including those outside the UK. Where appropriate, advice relevant to the specific circumstances must be obtained.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Data Protection Guidance</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/formalities/gdpr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/formalities/gdpr/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="data-protection-guidance"&gt;
 Data Protection Guidance
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#data-protection-guidance"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the &lt;a href="docs/glossary/#cccbr"&gt;CCCBR&lt;/a&gt; website and was written in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="overview"&gt;
 Overview
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#overview"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GDPR was applicable in EU member states from 25 May 2018. It did not require national legislation to be implemented and when the UK left the EU, the GDPR - like other directly applicable EU legislation - became part of the UK’s domestic law under the European Union (Withdrawal) Bill. The Data Protection Bill replaced the 1998 Data Protection Act (DPA), incorporates the GDPR and the Law Enforcement Directive into UK law and deals with permitted derogations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>