<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Health &amp; Safety on Running a Tower</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/</link><description>Recent content in Health &amp; Safety on Running a Tower</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><atom:link href="https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Health &amp; Safety Policy</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/healthsafetypolicy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/healthsafetypolicy/</guid><description>Health &amp;amp; Safety # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Advice for Bell Ringers # This document aims to help bell ringing societies/guilds/associations prepare a Health and Safety Policy for all activities of the society. (In these notes, the word society’ will be used regardless of the title of the society, guild or association concerned.)
Under common law, voluntary organisations and individual volunteers have a ‘duty of care’ to each other and to those who may be affected by their activities.</description></item><item><title>Risk Assessment</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/riskassessment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/riskassessment/</guid><description>Risk Assessment Guidance # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # Most towers with rings of bells are within the jurisdiction of the Church of England. While that is the focus of this document, the principles apply to rings of bells in towers owned by other organisations, in churches of other denominations, and churches elsewhere in the world. Local legislation and circumstances should always be considered.</description></item><item><title>Risk Assessment extended</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/riskassessmentextended/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/riskassessmentextended/</guid><description>Risk Assessment Guidance where the bells have not been rung for an extended period. # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # These notes offer advice about issues to consider in a health and safety risk assessment of the bells and tower prior to the bells being rung after an extended period (several months or more) during which they have not been rung.</description></item><item><title>Fire Protection</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/fireprevention/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/fireprevention/</guid><description>Fire Protection and Risk Assessment # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # These notes offer advice about specific issues that may affect bell ringers and the bell tower when considering fire safety and fire protection. The notes may assist the tower authority and bell ringers; they do not intend to provide comprehensive information about fire protection and fire risk assessments more generally.</description></item><item><title>Security</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/security/</guid><description>Security of Towers and Bell Ringers # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # These notes are written to help bell ringers consider their own security and that of the towers that they occupy when ringing. The principles underlying these notes apply to many buildings regardless of function or ownership, and activities. Here we highlight factors that relate specifically to ringers and ringing, rather than those that are more generic.</description></item><item><title>Tower Access</title><link>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/toweraccess/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://runningatower.cccbr.org.uk/docs/healthsafety/toweraccess/</guid><description>Tower Access # The following was previously published as a .pdf file on the CCCBR website.
Introduction # No matter how comfortable and well equipped your ringing room or how excellent the go of the bells, if you can&amp;rsquo;t reach them safely they&amp;rsquo;re not much use to you. For that reason it is well worth considering the state of the access route to the tower.
All towers are different and each will present a corresponding set of unique circumstances which will affect the decisions made with regard to the access route.</description></item></channel></rss>